{
    "id": "6eb9b442a44b45479d0e69cb797bf2e1",
    "title": "Reported Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Samuel said that he …………………………. to his friend’s house.",
            "description": "When the reporting verb is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the reported speech as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is going",
                "was going",
                "had been going"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Molly said that she ……………………………. to go.",
            "description": "When the reporting verb is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the reported speech as well.",
            "answers": [
                "wants",
                "wanted",
                "had wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Swapna says that she ………………………… the exam.",
            "description": "When the reporting verb is in the present tense, we can use a present tense in the reported speech as well.",
            "answers": [
                "has passed",
                "had passed",
                "have passed"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Asok said that his father …………………………. in Bangalore.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Bindu said that she …………………………… to Jaipur.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is going",
                "was going",
                "has gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie said that she ……………………………… a car.",
            "description": "A past tense in the direct speech changes to past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "bought",
                "has bought",
                "had bought"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Father asked me where ……………………………. going.",
            "description": "In indirect questions the subject goes before the auxiliary verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "I was",
                "did I"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My friend requested me …………………………… him to the library.",
            "description": "Imperatives are reported with a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "that accompany",
                "to accompany"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me where the bank ……………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know what …………………………. doing there.",
            "description": "In reported questions, the subject goes before the auxiliary verb.",
            "answers": [
                "are they",
                "they are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor suggested ………………………….. a long holiday.",
            "description": "Suggest cannot be followed by a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to take",
                "taking",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me ………………………… I was alright.",
            "description": "To introduce yes/no questions we use if or whether. ",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}